In this video, we're going to extend what we did earlier with Funk SVD,
在此视频中 我们将在 Funk SVD 的基础上
but enable ourselves to make
针对原本属于冷启动的情形
predictions where originally we were hit by the cold start problem.
作出预测
So, we saw in the previous video that we weren't able to make predictions
在上个视频中我们发现
when a user or a movie hadn't been in our training dataset,
如果某个用户或电影不在训练集中 但是出现在了测试集中
but then showed up in our testing dataset.
我们将无法对其做出预测
For those instances, in this notebook that we'll work on here,
对于这些情形 我们将在此 notebook 中
we'll actually make predictions using other methods besides Funk SVD.
使用除 Funk SVD 以外的其他方法做出预测
So, to start, we're actually going to read
首先 我们将读取
in a whole bunch of stuff that we used earlier,
之前使用过的多项内容
and also walk through these lines while they get written.
并且我将逐个介绍它们
Essentially, the first part,
在第一部分
we're going to read in our datasets.
我们将读取数据集
We are pulling in this create_train_test,
我们将提取此 create_train_test
which you used in the previous notebook.
你在之前的 notebook 中用过它
We're going to pull in this predict_rating,
还将提取 predict_rating
which pulls in our predictions using Funk SVD from the previous notebook.
它会使用上个 notebook 的 Funk SVD 提取预测
Then, down here at the bottom,
我在下面
you'll see that I'm creating the user by movie matrix,
创建了用户x电影矩阵
the same that we've been using throughout a number of the notebooks.
我们在多个 notebook 中使用了该矩阵
Down here in this last part,
然后在下面
I pickled the user matrix and
我对在上个 notebook 中使用 Funk SVD
the movie matrix that were created in the previous notebook using Funk SVD.
创建的用户矩阵和电影矩阵调用了 pickle()
Now I'm just pulling them in so that we can use them again in this notebook.
现在我获取它们以便在此 notebook 中使用它们
So, if we take a look at this,
看看矩阵
I'll just create a cell up here.
我在这创建一个单元格
Let's look at the user metrics.
我们来看看用户矩阵
So, the user matrix,
这是用户矩阵
and if we look at the shape, might be more helpful.
看看形状更有用
You can see that 3,278 is the number of users that we have in the training set,
训练集有 3,278 个用户
and we had 15 latent features.
潜在特征是 15 个
Then in the movie matrix,
在电影矩阵中
we had 15 features and 2,679 movies.
有 15 个特征和 2,679 部电影
So, this is the number of movies,
这是在之前的 notebook 中
and this was the number of latent features that we had from
对训练集应用 Funk SVD 后获得的
using Funk SVD on the training dataset in the previous notebook.
矩阵的电影数量和潜在特征数量
I basically just saved those in a way that
我保存了这些数据
we could pull them into this notebook and use them again here.
这样就能在此 notebook 中提取并使用这些数据
So, we want to make a comparison between each of
我们想要比较
our predictions and our actual values using Funk SVD where possible,
使用 Funk SVD 得出的每个预测值与真实值
and returned back some metrics on how well Funk SVD is
并返回一些指标 告诉我们 Funk SVD 的效果
doing and telling us what it would predict for a particular movie user combinations.
以及它针对特定的电影用户组合预测值是多少
So, I created three arrays,
我创建了三个数组
similar to what we actually have used in earlier notebooks,
与在之前的 notebook 中使用的数组相似
where essentially I took an array of the users.
我获取了用户数组
So, I pulled the users, and it might be helpful.
也就是提取了用户
So, if we look at the val_df,
有必要看看 val_df
remember this is just the validation data.
这是验证数据
So, we split our dataset into training and validation.
我们将数据集拆分成了训练集和验证集
The val_df is just the users and
val_df 是尚未传入
movie combinations that we haven't actually passed through our Funk SVD method.
Funk SVD 方法的用户和电影组合
So, we're going to make predictions on those to see how well we did.
我们将对这些组合进行预测 看看效果
So, I'm going to pull off the movie IDs.
我将提取 movie_id
Again, this looks a lot like what we did earlier.
这部分代码看起来和之前的很像
We're going to index into this to make sure we're pulling
我们将传入索引
the right spots in these arrays and then pulling
并确保进入这些数组的正确位置
the right row-column combinations from our user matrix and our movie matrix.
然后从用户矩阵和电影矩阵提取正确的行列组合
So you can see that I'm passing those in up here
我在这里传入了这些项
because we're going to be taking the dot product of
因为我们将计算用户行与电影列的点积
essentially a user row with a movie column to make our predictions.
从而做出预测
So, I'm going to create a couple of
我将创建几个
other variables that we're going to use throughout this function.
在此函数中一直使用的其他变量
One is the sums of squared error.
一个是平方误差和 sse
So, I'm going to keep track of what are some the squared error that
用 sse 跟踪平方误差
is and add to this as we make additional predictions.
并在做出其他预测时将平方误差加到这个变量上
I'm going to keep track of the number of ratings we make.
我还将记录评分数量
So, to start out with we'll have zero.
一开始这个值为 0
Then, I'm going to keep track of our predicted and actual values.
然后 我将跟踪预测值和真实值
I'm just going to store those in lists.
并将它们存储在列表中
I created this actual versus predicted.
我创建了这个实际值与预测值相比变量
Essentially, what this is,
它是这样的
I'm going to put actual on one axis,
我将实际值放在一个轴上
predicted on the other axis,
并将预测值放在另一个轴上
and then create a heatmap to
然后创建一个热图
understand how well my actual values are comparing against my predicted values.
看看实际值与预测值的比较情况
For every individual in the val_users,
对于 val_users 中的每一项
I'm just going to use the index of those and then
我将使用这些项的索引
I'll index into the different parts that we need.
然后转到不同的索引部分
I'm essentially going to try to do a prediction using Funk SVD,
我将尝试使用 Funk SVD 做出预测
but I'm going to raise an exception where we just
但是如果预测失败
continue on to the next individual if the prediction fails.
我将抛出异常并继续转到下一项
So, I'm going to use the predicted rating function that we had before.
我将使用之前创建的 predict_rating 函数
I'm going to use the user matrix,
我将使用用户矩阵
which is from Funk SVD that we read in with the pickle.
即通过 pickle() 从 Funk SVD 读取的矩阵
Here's the movie matrix that we read in with the pickle.
这是通过 pickle() 读取的电影矩阵
Then what I want is the user ID and the movie ID.
然后获取用户 ID 和电影 ID
So, I'm going to use the index,
我将使用 idx
and I'm going to pull those from val_users and then that index.
从 val_users 的这一索引处提取值
I want to pull from val_movies at that particular index and make a prediction.
并从 val_movies 的这一索引处提取值 然后做出预测
Then what I'm going to do is I'm going to look
接下来 我将查看预测值
at how far off my prediction is from the actual value.
与实际值相差多少
I'm going to take the prediction minus the actual,
用预测值减去实际值
where the actual is equal to val_ratings at that index,
实际值等于该索引处的 val_ratings
and then I'm going to square it so that they're all positive.
然后求平方 使它们都为正
So, this is going to keep track of my sum of the squared error.
这就是平方误差和
Then, basically, I'm going to add one to the number of ratings that we actually make.
接着使评分数量 num_rated 加一
So, notice, if the prediction fails,
注意 如果预测失败
we're just going to move to the accept.
我们将转到 except 部分
So, then nothing will get added to our sum of
这时候 平方误差和不变
the squared error and nothing will get added to our number of ratings.
评分数量也不会加一
Okay. Then I'm going to append the actual value to the actual list,
Ok然后将实际值附加到实际值列表上
and I'm going to append the predicted value to the predicted list.
并将预测值附加到预测值列表上
So, I'm going to append the prediction here.
在这里附加预测值
I'm going to append the actual value here.
并在这里附加实际值
Then in my actual versus prediction,
然后在 actual_v_pred 中
and this just took some getting used to.
这里需要花点时间理解
But essentially, what I'm doing is I'm going to index into
我将进入我创建的这个矩阵的索引中
this matrix that I'm creating and store a one where my predicted actual value falls.
并在预测实际值所在的位置存储一个 1
This will make more sense when I show you the picture.
用图片展示会更好理解
But essentially, I'm indexing in,
含义就是进入索引
and I'm just going to say add a one to that spot.
并在此位置加一
So, this is just a fancy indexing way to pinpoint exactly where I want to add that one.
这是一种比较复杂的确定索引方式 可以确定我要加一的具体位置
I'm adding that one wherever the predicted actual value falls on a 10 by 10 grid.
当预测实际值落入 10 x 10 网格 我将加一
From here, I'm going to update the rmse as
然后更新 rmse
the square root of the sum of squared error divided by the number of ratings we make.
它等于平方误差和除以评分数量
I'm going to keep track of the percent rated as basically the number of
然后跟踪评分百分比
rated divided by the length of val_users.
它等于评分数量除以 val_users 的长度
So, this is the total number of users,
这是用户总数
and we can keep track of the percentage
我们将跟踪能够使用 SVD
of individuals who were able to make ratings for using SVD.
做出评分的用户所占的百分比
Next, we're tasked with seeing how well this worked.
接下来我们将看看这部分的效果
I'm just going to copy this part.
复制这行代码
I'm going to rip this part up here and put an equal sign in between it.
并将这行代码放到这里 在中间添加一个等号
Oh, I did this before.
之前出现了这种错误
Sorry. This should be act versus predict. And I did.
抱歉这个应该是 act_v_pred然后...
Oh, this is act versus predict.
这个也应该是 act_v_pred
I did a print of the rmse and the percent rated.
我输出了 rmse 和 perc_rated
Then I also created this heatmap of the actual versus predicted,
还创建了这个实际值与预测值比较热图
and then I created a bunch of other labels here.
然后在这里创建了大量其他标签
I think I missed something up with this part.
这部分应该出错了
Oh, this is val_ratings index minus all that.
这里应该是 val_ratings[idx] 减去...
I should've known better.
不应该出错的
This is got to grab the real value rate.
这里获取的是实际值
So, this is got to grab the actual rating to know
即获取实际评分
where in the grid it falls. Let's try again.
看看它在网格的什么位置再试一遍
Cool. So, you can see,
好的可以看出
a majority of the points fall here,
大部分点都落在这里
where the predicted value is about a six,
预测值为 6
and the actual value is also about a six,
实际值也为 6
and most of the ratings fall in that range.
大部分评分都在这个范围内
You can see that not very many of the values fall in this range up here.
这个区域没有多少值
We could look at some other metrics, but essentially,
我们可以看看其他矩阵
we're missing by about 2.04 on any of those ratings
所有这些评分相差约 2.04
and we're able to make predictions for about 50 percent of them.
我们能够对大约 50% 的组合做出预测
We can see how well we were able to make predictions by looking at the number of ratings
我们可以将可用的评分数量乘以 perc_rated
that were available and look at the percent rated times that.
看看我们的预测效果
So, essentially, for the number of ratings that were available,
在已有数量的评分中
we were able to make predictions for about 960 of them.
我们能够对其中的 960 个做出预测
Similarly, if we look at one minus that,
同理 如果括号里是 1-perc_rated
there were about 1,400 individuals that we weren't able to make ratings for.
结果显示大约有 1,400 项无法做出预测